{
    "id": "96_Politics_562",
    "claim": "In an obvious (indirect) response to the approach that Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador would seek with Pope Francis I to resolve the problem of violence in Mexico, the pontiff expressed a position of rejection against those who use the poor for political purposes, as the so-called 'messianic leader 'does. During a July sermon by , the Catholic monarch told the faithful that ideologies are bad, partial and useless, and set as an example that in the last century the countries where ideologies were applied became dictatorships. Populism and socialism are ideologies that were implemented in several countries last century and failed. Some notable examples are Chile, Argentina and, most recently; Venezuela. I'm sorry.",
    "source": "www.laotraopinion.com.mx",
    "date": "15/04/2018",
    "veracity": 0,
    "claims": [
        {
            "claim": "In an obvious (indirect) response to the approach that Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador would seek with Pope Francis I to resolve the problem of violence in Mexico, the pontiff expressed a position of rejection against those who use the poor for political purposes, as the so-called 'messianic leader 'does.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What does Lopez Obrador refer to as?",
                    "answer": "'messianic leader"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What position did Andres Manuel Lopez Obrador take on those who use the poor for political purposes?",
                    "score": 0.7611,
                    "answers": "a position of rejection against those who use the poor for political purposes|dobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Andres Manuel Obrador's position on the problem of violence in Mexico?",
                    "score": 0.6057,
                    "answers": "political purposes|pobj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "During a July sermon by , the Catholic monarch told the faithful that ideologies are bad, partial and useless, and set as an example that in the last century the countries where ideologies were applied became dictatorships.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did the Catholic monarch tell the faithful that ideologies are bad, partial and useless?",
                    "answer": "a July sermon by"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What did the Catholic monarch say about ideologies?",
                    "score": 0.8314,
                    "answers": "useless|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "How many countries were influenced by ideologies in the last century?",
                    "score": 0.7278,
                    "answers": "in the last century|prep\tthat in the last century the countries where ideologies were applied became dictatorships|ccomp"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the names of the countries where ideologies were applied to ideologies?",
                    "score": 0.718,
                    "answers": "dictatorships|attr"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the name of the country where ideologies were applied?",
                    "score": 0.695,
                    "answers": "set as an example that in the last century the countries where ideologies were applied became dictatorships|conj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Populism and socialism are ideologies that were implemented in several countries last century and failed.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "What ideologies were implemented in several countries last century and failed?",
                    "answer": "Populism and socialism"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What countries have tried to implement Populism and socialism?",
                    "score": 0.888,
                    "answers": "that were implemented in several countries last century and failed|relcl\tin several countries|prep\tseveral countries|pobj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What are the origins of Populism and socialism?",
                    "score": 0.8181,
                    "answers": "Populism and socialism|nsubj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is socialism?",
                    "score": 0.7999,
                    "answers": "socialism|conj"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of the success of socialism and Populism in other countries last century?",
                    "score": 0.7575,
                    "answers": "www.laotraopinion.com.mx|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "claim": "Some notable examples are Chile, Argentina and, most recently; Venezuela.",
            "question_answers": [
                {
                    "question": "When did www.laotraopinion.com.mx report that Chile, Argentina and Venezuela were some notable examples?",
                    "answer": "15/04/2018"
                }
            ],
            "focal_questions": [
                {
                    "question": "What are some examples of Chilean countries being influenced by socialism?",
                    "score": 0.8778,
                    "answers": "and|cc\t;|punct"
                },
                {
                    "question": "What is the source of evidence of Chilean and Chilean political views?",
                    "score": 0.7755,
                    "answers": "www.laotraopinion.com.mx|nsubj"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}